RUOYANG XIONG

ALGORITHM / SOFTWARE ENGINEER \$\square\$ 3522222558

• DETAILS •

352222558 ruoyangxiong@gmail.com

o LINKS o

Homepage

GitHub

LinkedIn

SKILLS

C++

Python

Framework Designing

Complex Problem Solving

Leadership Skills

Git

JIRA

Document Writing

LANGUAGES

English

Chinese

PROFILE

Experienced C++ engineer with 6 years of software design and 3 years of team management experience. During my tenure at MYNTAI, I was mainly responsible for the SDK for the binocular camera which brought 10 million RMB profit yearly. The product attracted a personal investment of 30 million RMB by Mr. Chen, chairman of Shentong Express Co., Ltd. During my tenure at INDEMIND, I lead the refactor of SDK for a visual camera product, and the annual sales of the product went from 1000 to 4000 units in one year. I led software development for an automatic washing machine product, which received investment from cleaning equipment giant ICE. For now, I'm a master's student majoring in Computer Science at the University of Florida working on machine learning research in the SERMOS lab.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science, University of Florida, Gainesville

August 2021 — Present

- GPA: 3.89
- · Student Assistant at the SERMOS LAB

Bachelor of Intelligence Science and Technology, Hebei University of Technology, Tianjin

September 2011 — July 2015

- Won the second class prize in the National Electronic Design Competition(Team)
- Participated in Formula Student China Competition(Team)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Student Assistant at University of Florida, Gainesville

October 2021 — Present

- Matched accuracy escaping routes of survivals in a terrific wildfire based on Markov chain by using real GPS data.
- Evaluated the reasonableness of the urban road network design in Sonoma by analyzing the routing choices during the wildfire.
- Analyzed the route choices of survivors and their influencing factors.

C++ Engineer / SDK Group Leader at Indemind Inc., Beijing

February 2020 — August 2021

- Designed the software framework of a kind of visual camera product.
- Managed the software development of a large-scale automatic washing machine product.
- Led the revolution of the JIRA workflow and the Git workflow.

C++ Engineer / SDK Group Leader at MYNT AI Inc., Beijing

September 2016 — February 2020

- Designed the SDK of the binocular camera product.
- Led the development of a custom binocular camera product for Alibaba.
- Designed the software of a kind of auto-calibration device and **obtained an invention patent**.